DMYTRO AFANASIEV

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

CONTACTS:

Calgary, Alberta, Canada | +15879699718 | dimaafanasiev3@gmail.coм

SUMMARY:

Frontend Developer with over 5 years of experience in React.js, Vue.js, Typescript and Tailwind. Delivered 30+ web projects on time. Demonstrated ability in leading teams to increase efficiency and manage projects effectively. Passionately committed to continuous learning and staying current with evolving industry trends and technologies.

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Cornerstone Digital, Calgary, Alberta, Canada February 2022 - May 2023 FRONTEND DEVELOPER

- Developed over 15 e-commerce websites using React.js, TypeScript, and Tailwind, leading to a 40% increase in sales
- · Synchronized effectively with the backend team to merge frontend and backend elements, reducing interface issues
- Optimized the code to enhance website load times by 30%, resulting in an improved user experience
- · Introduced comprehensive testing and quality checks, reducing issues discovered postlaunch by 30%
- Maintained a well-organized and clear codebase by following best coding practices

oXyShop, Brno, Czech Republic April 2021 - January 2022 FRONTEND DEVELOPER

- Brought to life 20+ new features for e-shops using Vue.js, Nuxt.js, TypeScript and **Tailwind**
- Applied effective communication skills to collaborate with the backend development team to integrate frontend and backend functionality
- Improved overall UI and troubleshoot issues during development in Agile environment
- Performed code reviews and implemented best practices, resulting in a 15% improvement in code quality and maintainability
- Implemented Cypress for testing, reducing the number of post-deployment issues by 25%

Bold Identities, UK, Remote TEAM LEAD FRONTEND DEVELOPER June 2020 - March 2021

- Managed a development team of 5, ensuring projects for recruitment agencies were delivered in a timely and efficient manner using leadership skills
- · Collaborated with clients to meet their needs, always paying close attention to detail and easily adapting to changes
- · Utilized HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js, and Next.js to develop high-quality, userfriendly websites
- · Performed code reviews and utilized modern managing practices in Agile environment resulting increased team efficiency by 30%

FRONTEND DEVELOPER Bold Identities, UK, Remote May 2018 - August 2020

- · Applied HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, along with React.js and Next.js, in the development of UI for high-quality web applications.
- Executed 30+ design mockups, maintained frontend features, and collaborated with team to meet or exceed deadlines
- Developed a new design system that reduced design-to-development time by 25% and integrated frontend and backend functionality using innovation and computer programming skills

EDUCATION:

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE: INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

Brno University of Technology - Brno, Czech Republic September 2021 - Current

JUNIOR SPECIALIST: INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

Kharkiv Radio Engineering College - Kharkiv, Ukraine September 2017 - June 2021

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

- Frontend: HTML5, CSS (Tailwind, Bootstrap, SASS), JavaScript (React.js, Next.js, Vue.js, Nuxt.js, Blazor), TypeScript
- State Management: Redux, Vuex, Pinia
- Backend: Node.js, PHP, Twig
- Database: MySQL, MongoDB
- Cloud Services: Firebase, Azure, AWS
- Module bundlers: Webpack, Rollup.js
- Testing: Cypress, Jest
- Containerization Tools: Docker, Docker Compose APIs: REST, GraphQL
- Package managers: npm, yarn, pnpm
- · Design Tools: Figma, Adobe XD
- IDEs: PhpStorm, Visual Studio Code
- Operating Systems: Windows, Linux Version Control: GIT (GitHub and GitLab)
- Project Management: Agile, Scrum, Jira

LANGUAGES:

- English (B2)
- · Czech (B2)
- Ukrainian (Native)
- Russian (Native)

LINKS:

HTTPS://WWW.LINKEDIN.COM/IN/DMYTRO-AFANASIEV-216574219/